hey guys I think this is kind of a cool
one it's asking for the area of this
rectangle that contains these three unit
circles so the area of a rectangle is
base times height so we just need to
find the base and the height so first
let's do the base let's start with this
circle the radius is equal to one so
this radius would also be equal to one
now for this circle this radius is one
so this radius is also one so the base
of this rectangle is going to be equal
to one two three four centimeters that
was the easy one now we got to do the
height so this is a radius of a circle
that's equal to one and this right here
would also be equal to the radius of one
of these circles and those are pretty
easy to spot but this green portion is
not quite so easy but we can still find
the length of this green part let's
complete the right triangle right here
this side of the triangle is equal to
one centimeter because it is the radius
of this circle and this piece right here
is also one centimeter because it's a
radius and this piece right here is
equal to one centimeter because it's a
radius so now we have a nice right
triangle let's pull it out this side is
equal to one and this side is equal to
two and our unknown side length we'll
call X centimeters since it's a right
triangle we can do the Pythagorean
theorem one squared plus x squared is
equal to 2 squared 1 squared is equal to
one two squared is equal to four then we
can subtract 1 from both sides these
cancel each other out and four minus 1
is equal to 3. we can square root both
sides and we get X is equal to square
root of three so the length of this
green segment is square root of three
centimeters so the length of this side
of the rectangle is going to be equal to
1 plus the square root of three plus one
centimeters and then one plus one is
equal to two so now we have our height 2
plus root 3 centimeters the area of a
rectangle is equal to base times height
the base is equal to four and the height
is equal to two plus root three so our
area is going to be equal to four times
two which is eight plus four times root
three and we got to give it a label of
centimeters squared this is the answer
to the question this is the area of the
rectangle let's put a box around it how
exciting